Guide to the Elliott Reid Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Elliott Reid papers
1924-1966
SC0230
Reid, Elliott, 1900-1968.
4.75 Linear feet
Correspondence, research notes and drawings, reports, articles, product specifications, commercial publications, photographs, and other items pertaining to airplanes and aeronautical research, including his research on wings and propellers. There is correspondence with the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and aircraft companies such as Boeing, Douglas, Northrop, and Lockheed. Correspondents include Col. Homer A. Boushey, Louis B. Gratzer, George J. Higgins, E.P. Lesley, G.W. Lewis, Earl C. Popp, L. Prandtl, and D.D. Warner. Collection also includes research logs and bills from research conducted for Tracerlab, Inc., of Berkeley, 1949-54.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Transferred by School of Engineering, 1980 and 1985
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of aeronautics at Stanford (1929-1965). Reid was the author of APPLIED WING THEORY, 1932, and many technical papers published by the National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics.
Description of the Collection
The papers of Elliot G. Reid, dating from 1924 to 1966, document his research interests in aeronautics and his professional career at Stanford University. Included in the papers are correspondence, research notes and drawings, reports, articles, product specifications, commercial publications, and photographs. Research subjects include fundamentals in aerodynamics, wing sections, complete wings, bodies, internal aerodynamics, propellors, rotors, airplanes, engines, and instruments. There are correspondence files for the National Advisory Committee on Aeronautics (NACA), the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA), and aircraft companies such as Boeing, Douglas, Northrop, and Lockheed. Major correspondents include Col. Homer A. Boushey, Louis B. Gratzer, George J. Higgins, E.P. Lesley, G. W. Lewis, Earl C. Popp, Ludwig Prandtl, and D. D. Warner. Also included in the papers are research logs, bills, and travel vouchers from research Reid conducted for Tracerlab, Inc., of Berkeley, 1949-1954.
Arrangement
The first half of the collection, arranged by numbered subjects, reflects Professor Reid's original arrangement. The second half was received roughly alphabetized; this order was clarified during processing and several new folders were devised. Paper clips have been removed and the materials were re-foldered in acid-free folders. His original subject dividers were retained; a new divider indicating the beginning of the alphabetical files was added.
Access Terms
Boushey, Homer A., Col.; Gratzer, Louis B.; Higgins, George J.; Lesley, Everett Parker.; Lewis, G.W.; Popp, Earl C.; Prandtl, L. (Ludwig), b. 1875.; Reid, Elliott, 1900-1968.; Stanford University. Department of Aeronautics and Astronautics. Faculty.; United States. National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics.; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration.; Warner, D.D.; Aeronautics--Research.; Airplanes--Wings.; Engineering drawings.; Photoprints.; Propellers, Aerial.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - 1.1 Fundamental
    - AE 229 Notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aerod. Research - Universities (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Aerod. Smoothness – Lockheed (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Aerodynamic Heating (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Alternating Flow (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - AWT Biplane Incidence (Revision) (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Biplane Lift - Tahi and Ground Effect (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Boundary Layer - Burghers (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Calculation of Flow Air and Diatomic Gasses (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Circ. Cyl. -Asym. Flow (GJH) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Coandra Effect (References) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Comp Flow About Bodies of Revolution (Sears), Misc. Papers on (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dissipative Mechanism - Liber (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Douglas - Theoretical Aerod. Reports list (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Electrolytic Tank - TMB (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Expansions - Navier Stokes Equations (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Fluid Mechanisms in Aero. Development - Patterson (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Glauert - Notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hyperballistics (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Induced Drag of Any Biplane (ACIC) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Integrals (Green) (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Karman, Comp. Flow - Notes (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Katzmayr, Effect (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Lifting...Theory - Sears (Integral Equations Solutions Eigenvalues) (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Magnethydrodynamics (PAI) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Magnus Effect - Note Latch (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Meier-Windhorst (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Multiplane Computations (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - No Down Draft Ventilator (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Nozzle Flow - London (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Oscillating Airfoil (Misc. Notes) (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Potential Flow Analogs (Electrolytic Tank, etc.) (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Prandtl - Contributions to Wing Theory (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Reactions - Choked Flow (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Rotating Cylinders and Flap Papers: 1. Regenscheit; 2. Favre (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Rotating Cylinders (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Schoenherr - Turb S.F. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Separated Flow - H.S. Tan (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Shadowgraphs (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Smoke Flow - Lippisch (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Sonic Boom (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Spheres (Rate of Fall in Water) (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Stack Model (Stiffness and Damping) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Stack Vibration (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Tacoma Bridge (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Wood ID (T. Aer., 2nd) Answers (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Thermal Properties of Gasses (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Total Head Evaluation (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Total Pressure Evaluation (In Non-Uniform Stream) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Vortex Theory (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Wall Effect on Tailsetting (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1.21 Wing Sections
    - Airfoil Ordinates (Joukowski and Bipolar) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Flap Data (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Joukowski Airfoils (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - The Theory of Lift of Airfoils (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Profile Drag (R&M 1838) (Squier and Young) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1.22 Complete wings
    - CL Max - Swept Wings (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Dihedral - A.G. Shift, etc. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Extensible Ailerone (AMC...etc.) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Hsiao - Thesis (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Oscillating Airfoil...Cicola (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Oscillating Airfoil-M.I.T. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Oscillating Airfoil - Preliminary Calculations (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - P.D.- NACA 81-J (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1.3 Bodies
    - Fuselage Drag (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Supersonic Induction System (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1.4 Internal Aerodynamics
    - Diffusers - Notes and Suggestions (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - H.S. Diffusers - Naumann - Trs. W.F. Davis (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1.5 Propellers
    - Aeromatic (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Analysis of Profile Effects (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Blade Form Curves and Summary 1929 Results (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Calculations - High Pitch Blades for Tandem Props (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Continental Sky Power (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Counter Rotating Propellers - McCoy (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - FS Prop. Selection Data from TR 351 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - HS 23D40 Hub. Dim. and CG (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Jacuzzi Windmills (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - NACA Models A-G and Blade Drawings (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Olmstead Prop. Data (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Shank Cuffs (Wood) Pat. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Smith Lycoming V. P. Propeller (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Synchrophasing (Lockheed) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Tandem Air Propellers II Original Tests, Fig EPL (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Wing Lift in Slipstream-Rethorst (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1.6 Rotors
    - Helicopters (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Hiller (Stuart) Rotor (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Kirkwood - Helio (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1.7.1 Airplanes
    - Airplanes Perf. Des. Charts - Brunk (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - BAC Take-Off Test Data 247 D and DC-3A (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Boening 727 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Convair 340 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Convair 340 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - DC-3, -4 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - DC-6, Data (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - DC-9 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Enemy Aircraft Catalog (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - General Electric - P59 Flight Tests (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Heinemann - High Speed Aircraft Develop. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Martin (Seaplane Pursuit) Reports (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Norair - X21 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - P-80 Data (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Rate of Climb Charts (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Warner - Notes and Corrections (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Lateral Control (Extensible) [Disclosure] (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Report on Flight in the Stratosphere (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "Everyman's Airplane" - Weick (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Superaerodynamics (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Hemke - Airplane Drag (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Stratosphere Flight - Woodyatt (empty) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Landing Speed Reduction (Review by D. Kaplan) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Log. Perf. Prediction - Carlo Alippi - Guidonia (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - 1.7.1.3 Airplane Performance
    - Ground Run - Garbell (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Mollinger on F86D Speed Trials (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Alloc. of Fuel and Cargo for Max. Ton-Miles - Petroff (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - L.P.C. Method - Curtiss (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Schairer - Airplane Slide Rule (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Maximum Speed Analysis (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Landing Speed Analysis (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - 1.7.2 Missiles
    - Missile Perf. Estimation - K.D. Wood (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - 1.7.5 Airships
    - RS-1 Tests (ACIC) (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - 1.8 Stability Control and Flying Quality
    - Aerod. Boosted Controls (Dunn-Douglas) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Dynamic Stability Notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Spinning (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Dyn. Long. Stability (Warner) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Stability Questionnaire (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Stall Warning (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - A. F. Reports on Stab. and Cont. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Gr. Effect on Downwash (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Uncontrolled spins - Korvin-Kroukovsky (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Aileron Effect - Weiselsberger (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Aileron Analysis (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1.9 Aerodynamic Loading
    - Gust and Vv Effects (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - 1.10 Vibration and Flutter
    - Wing Flutter (Brady model) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Parachutes - Heinrich (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - 3.1.1 Recriprocal Engines
    - Wasp S1H1 - G Drawing and data (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Wasp Jr. - SB. Drawing and power data (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - 3.1.3 Turbo-Jets
    - JT3E Performance Curves (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - T-J Performance - London ('60) (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - 3.1.7 Ram Jet
    - Propulsion spectrum (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - 3.1.8 Rocket
    - Rockets (Krzywoblocki) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - 3.6 Compressors
    - Slotted blade ax. blower (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Compressor - Rotating Stall (W.R.Sears) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Supercharger (Szydlowski - Planiol) (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - 3.7 Turbines
    - Gas Turb. and Jet Propulsion, Westinghouse (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - 4. Structures
    - Annular diaphragms (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - 5. Materials
    - Wood (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - 6. Meteorology
    - Jet stream (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Marianas Std. Day (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Mountain wave zones, United States (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Mountain wave (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Std. atmosphere - British (1942) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Data - std. atmos. - 1959 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Lightning and aircraft (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - 7. Operating Problems
    - Celestial navigation (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Misc. operating hazards (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - 8. Instruments
    - Fluid controls (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - T.H. tube shielded - Boeing (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Orifices (AAF TR 4552) (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Autopilot Devel. - Lear (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Doppler Navig. Instr. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Velocity meas. - by tracer (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Inertial guidance (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sperry "vibragyro" (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - MIT airfoil oscillator (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Angle-of-attack and angle-of-yaw indicator..., Navy report by Robert B. Ormsby, Jr. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Altimeter errors (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Attenuation of oscill. press in tubes (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - A.S. capsule (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Analog computers (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Total head tubes (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Wind vane - geology dept. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Cylindrical yaw head (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - S & W airspeed head (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - 9. Research Equipment and Technique
    - Georgia Tech (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Discussion UC low density tunnel (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Cornell (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Boeing - Allen Mem. Lab. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - C.I.T. Co-Op Tunnel (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - C.I.T. Tunnel (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Wattendorf - Tsing Hue Tunnel and efficiency of return flow tunnels (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Wind tunnel drives (Westinghouse and GE) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Cornell Aero Lab (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - NACA - Moffett (12' press) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Marquardt Supersonic (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Static press. grad. (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Stanford Research Institute (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Aerolab (Merrill) tunnel (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - 10. Nomenclature
    - Wartime reports list (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - 12. Technical Summaries
    - SRI reprints (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Colloidal state (Bender) (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Minimum drag - warped SS wings (Anliker) (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Contrails (Cornell) (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Nuclear physics (clippings) (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Radioactivity in stratosphere (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Analysis - 100 mt burst (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Fine particles - Turkevich (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Klemperer - Advent of astronautics (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Satellite orbits (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Air properties at high temp. (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Inertial navigation (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Alphabetical Files
    - AE 229 notes (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - AIAA - correspondence, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Air Research and Development Command - Office of Sci. Res., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Allen, E.T. (Boeing) - correspondence, 1928-1965 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - American men of science - data (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Armed Services Technical Information Agency (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Armed Services Technical Information Agency; Field of Int. Reg. Code No. (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Attinello, J.S. - Fairchild (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Babberger, C. (Hughes) - correspondence, 1953-1965 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Barricklow, John - correspondence, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Bechtel Corporation (W.L. Dickey) - correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Bechtel requisitions (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Besseling, Johannes (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Boushey, Col. Homer A. - correspondence, 1946-1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Boushey, Col. Homer A. - correspondence and notes, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Brentnall, S.R. - correspondence, 1939-1964 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Carter, John H. - letter of recommendation (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Cessna Aircraft Co. - correspondence, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Chadwick, Joe - correspondence, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Civil Engineering (Thesis Publ.) '55 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Congress - correspondence with members, 1944-1946 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cons. exp. work - 1949-54 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Convair - correspondence and notes, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Convair - contracts, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Convair - correspondence and notes, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Daniel, John, Jr. Gift Fund (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Diffuser test correspondence, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Douglas sky rule instructions (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Durand, William F. - biographical (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Engineers Joint Council (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Enigmas (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Faculty rating survey (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Finch, Volney Cecil - memorial (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Fogel, Karen Sydnie Trust (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Gough, Mel - correspondence, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Griswold II, Roger - correspondence, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Ground cooling tests, 2nd series (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Heppe, R.R. - correspondence, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - HIASD - correspondence, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Hoberg and Finger, Propeller Blade Analysis - consulting report, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Hughes - log, 1953-54 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Hughes Tool Company, Aircraft Division - report and correspondence, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Income tax duplicates (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Income tax 1945 (Est. 1946) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Inoculation records (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Insurance (faculty life insurance) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Jacobsen, L.S. - reprint (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Clarence - Lockheed - correspondence, 1936-1946 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Johnston, Paul (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Kahle, Keith [Meteor Design] - correspondence, 1940 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - von Karman, Th. - correspondence, 1932-1956 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Kelly, Howard R. - NOTS (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Lab serial number (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Ladden, I.M. - correspondence, 1960-1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Ladder problem (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Lesley memorial resolution (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Lion hunting ["A contribution to the mathematical theory of big game hunting," by H. Petard] (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Lockheed Missiles and Space Company (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Los Alamos requisitions (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Los Alamos invoices, bills, receipts, misc. records (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Los Alamos - Cost estimate (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - McGraw-Hill - royalty statements and contract (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - McGraw-Hill - AWT copyright (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - McGraw-Hill 1957-1958 - correspondence (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Map - Edwards AFB (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Medical care plans (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Univ. of Michigan Eng. Deg. - correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Mosler safe instructions (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - S.C. Mossop - correspondence, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - NACA Aircraft engineering research conference, 1936 - typescript notes (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - NACA - M.E. dept proposals - 1953 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - NACA 1950-55 - correspondence (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - NACA 1956-60 - correspondence (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - NACA errata (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - NASA 1961-65 - correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - NASA Misc. Doc. Req. 1962 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - NASA Langley inspection 1964 [metal disk] (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - National Research Council - correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - National Science Foundation - correspondence, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Niles letter 1959 [Reid to Alfred Niles] (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Northrop Ventura consulting agreement, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Northrop Ventura correspondence 1965 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Northrop - calc. and misc. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Packing of spheres - notes (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Parcel post guide (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Patent agreement, 1963 (Reid with Stanford University) (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Post war program 1944 [correspondence concerning] (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Price, Peter - "Suppression of the fluid-induced vibration of circular cylinders," typescript and two reprints, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Price, Peter and Robert Thompson [correspondence re joint thesis] (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Projectile motion - typescript paper (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Publications - E.G. Reid (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Publishers - directory (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Research Contract Procedure," by Moses Terman (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Royal Aeronautical Society (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Schick, H.M. - correspondence, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Secrecy agreements, 1944-1951 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Slide projector (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Social security [Stanford payroll info] (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Stanford Building Products Co. - correspondence, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Stanford broadcast [on streamlining of automobiles, 1935] - text and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Stanford, pre-appointment correspondence, 1925, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Stanford Research Institute - Lloyd I. Krause (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Streamlined bodies - lecture (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Swanson, W.M. - Case Institute of Technology - correspondence, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Tunnel specifications (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Tracerlab Materials
    - Bills and travel vouchers, 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Log 1950 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Log, bills, etc., 1951 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Log and bills, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Log, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Bills and travel vouchers, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Log, bills, and miscellaneous consulting, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Papers
    - Report on an Aerodynamic Investigation of a...Motorcar, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Roberts, Howard E., thesis photos (not used) for "The effect of propeller-shank cuffs upon cooling flow and propeller performance," by Howard Emery Roberts and Richard deHart Williams, circa 1940 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous photos of equipment and a graph (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Reid, "A Brief Outline of the History of Aeronautics Prepared Especially for Students," 37 pages, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
SELECTED CORRESPONDENTS FROM SUBJECT FILES
Dickey, D.A. (Army Air Force) Box 2, Folder 17
Gratzer, Louis B. Box 1, Folder 34
Higgins, George J. Box 5, Folder 4
Lesley, E. P. Box 1, Folder 29
Lesley, E. P. Box 3, Folder 16
Lesley, E. P. Box 3, Folder 14
Lewis, G.W. (NACA) Box 1, Folder 31
Monteith, C.N. (Boeing) Box 5, Folder 4
Popp, Earl C. (Dept. of Commerce) Box 3, Folder 26
Prandtl, Ludwig Box 1, Folder 33
Raymond, A.E. (Douglas Aircraft) Box 5, Folder 4
Sears, William R. Box 5, Folder 7
Warner, D.D. (Northrop) Box 4, Folder 5
Alippi, Carlo Box 4, Folder 16